On the street, on the balconies, or on the terrace,
on the ground floor,
this evening, at 7 o'clock,
everyone goes to the nation!
I was 12 and a half years old.
It was a day of the end of spring 1940,
when you saw it for the first time.
I remember it very well, because of that merit,
while Mussolini declared war on France and Great Britain,
I had my first bicycle.
Laiomai, Mozzi Adala, Manobrio D'Ambrosio,
Cerchione, Bianchi, Porcelli, Legnano,
Campio, Vittorio and Margherita Adala.
A work, a regular day.
The chain, but it's new.
I have to buy it now.
What are you doing?
What are those new ones?
Look, now that there's water,
let's throw ourselves out of my bicycle.
Contattanti,
Vittorio,
Di Marce,
Sotarga,
Sanita Nero,
and Trinitone,
Guadalajara,
and D'Ambrosio,
Arzonsate.
CHEERING
LAUGHTER
Now you're a man, Vittorio.
Hello, Missy.
What are you doing?
I'm going to the toilet.
Come on, Vittorio!
I don't like you going to the toilet
to finish the whole thing.
Why? What are you doing?
You're going to see something.
CHEERING
Come on, come on!
Oh, what do you say?
Shhh.
It's lucky.
Professor Tradino.
What's his name?
Kimballo Stecco!
Hello.
Where's the phone?
I think it's because of the earphone.
What?
It's a problem.
What's the name?
The most expensive part of Casta & Cutor.
The sun is bigger than the moon.
That is, the sun is bigger than the moon.
I don't know, but I can take it from your son Malé.
All right, take it.
Love is no longer of wealth.
The sun is bigger than the moon.
That is, the sun is bigger than the moon.
The sun, the sun!
1, 2, 3 and 2 and 5 and 2, 7 and 2 and odd!
I told you I wanted to change, and I'm from Malena.
Once in Malena, I was called.
One morning, I went to school, I went to Sicily,
and I passed in front of the house of Malena.
The idea was fake, but it was what I was expecting.
And I thought I wanted cigarettes.
But next door, next door, next door,
I had to solve it.
And while I was next door, I opened the window.
Minghi, I saw him naked like his mother.
Minghi!
Minghi, but I didn't do it on purpose, I was provoked.
But I was a coward, I didn't know how to do it.
But the next time he called me for cigarettes,
I was taken to Malena.
It's pretty much a smoke bomb, you know.
But I know he's a big idiot.
You're going to tell Minghi that he's playing with a gun,
with a knife and a spear.
You're going to tell Minghi that you're going to kill him.
One, two, three, four, five...
Are you serious?
One that has a knife and a gun,
that can have a place for Minghi.
A knife and a gun?
You're going to tell Minghi that you're going to kill him.
Yes!
Who are you?
Salsa! Salsa! Salsa! Salsa!
Tell me, who is the longest friend?
Salsa! Salsa!
Let's get to know Minghi.
You're going to tell Minghi that you're going to kill him.
Granada, Granada, San Diego...
Can't do this to me.
Go to the car and wait for the bus.
I'll be on my way to the exit.
Can you take me there?
No, I can't.
I'm not going anywhere.
That is the latest case from your wife.
I'll get you a new car soon.
I'm talking about money,
and she'll be here on my way home.
Okay.
Hey, hey, take this money.
I'm going to the car!
Don't worry!
I will buy her a new one!
Okay, I'll get it, Mother!
I said, I'm so grateful to you!
Thank you for this time!
Gonna take the money!
We already got that car!
Got it, Mark!
OK, got it!
I want your cigarette.
Let me have it.
I'll have it.
My hand!
I'm wearing your father's clothes.
I didn't wear it for 23 years.
It looks like you're getting married today.
It's only the wedding day.
He says he wants to wear it only when he's dead.
Of course.
If you show your father with a cut like this,
or if you put a piece of paper on it, it won't work.
My father is still young.
And you still think you're too young
to wear long pants?
Yes, you have to do your own thing.
I'll do it.
Father, do you agree?
Of course I agree.
You go to the jump to make them adapt.
Don't use your father's clothes!
Don't you understand me?
Don't you dare to be afraid of your father's clothes!
But I don't feel ashamed to wear short pants!
You like it, don't you?
Enough, listen to us!
I'll tell you who you don't want to see
with your sister-in-law's clothes!
Let's do a parties.
El giorno que qualcuno spacchiera la testa in due a quien vivo io.
Allora ti farò i bantaloni lungi.
E giura.
Bantaloni lungi.
matière.
La Piazza, una batteria è stata centrata, sono stati notati incendi e d'asplosioni.
Un nostro belivolo non è rientrato.
Aerei nemici hanno lanciato nuovamente alcune bombe su Benghazi e località viciniori.
Nell'Africa Orientale, il mattino dell'Undici, una forza navale angolo-indiana
è presentata davanti a Stade, ha bombardato la città già scomberata
dalle nostre truffe e l'ha occupata.
Nella zona di Conta, dettativi di attacco contro
nostre posizioni di walk-in sono stati incendi e d'asplosioni
impredendo al nemico centinaia di perdite.
Altre formazioni nemiche, appoggiate da azioni aeree di bombardamento
e di traggiamento, hanno attaccato in forse il nostro presidio di Debra Tabor.
Sono state respinte e contraattaccate in seguite
e mi traciate dalla nostra canzine di canna
SONANTA
Certo, una donna bella e giovane, come lei, come fa, stanisense?
Eh?
Ti può stare a parare?
Ma lei ne escondia?
Ah, figlia, tua usurga.
Nenche se lo avete, ho in questi occhi, ci credo, che non c'ha nessuno.
Une, c'è...
Io?
Cavalieri?
Pure prime, quando era signorine.
E che lo sa?
Come che lo sa?
The week after tomorrow, he'll come back to the body.
He's going to the war.
Who's going to put his hand on the fire?
There's no way out.
That's right!
Why don't you let me go with the guys?
You're still too young to be on the side of the big ones.
The day after tomorrow, he'll come back to the body.
My son, if you don't know the title, how can I give it to you?
What a romantic song!
But love can't, my love can't.
But love can't, he wanted to tell us so much.
My son, tell us.
It was the song of Lidavaglia.
10 Lidavaglia at the house.
And I won't try it.
And you never know, it might be a defect.
I won't try it.
Lidavaglia